Hello English learners and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎来到EnglishPod。我是Marco。
I'm Amira.
我是Amira。
Amira and I are here today with another interesting and useful lesson for you English learners.
今天Amira和我为你们英语学习者带来了另一节有趣且实用的课程。
Amira, why don't you explain a little bit of what this lesson is about today?
Amira，不如你简单介绍一下今天这节课的内容？
It's about calling in sick.
是关于请病假的。
Oh, okay. That's useful.
哦，好的。这很实用。
Yes, definitely. It happens to everyone once in a while. You don't feel so well or you
是的，确实。每个人偶尔都会遇到这种情况。你感觉不太舒服，或者
feel well but you don't want to go to work.
你感觉还好但就是不想去上班。
Right.
对。
So, you call in sick.
所以，你就打电话请病假。
Okay. Okay. Let's listen to this dialogue and I want everyone to keep their ears open
好的，好的。我们来听这段对话，我希望大家竖起耳朵听好，
and see if the boss believes this person.
看看老板是否相信这个人。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Hello, Daniel speaking. How may I help you?
你好，我是丹尼尔。有什么可以帮您的？
Hi Daniel. Julie here.
嗨，丹尼尔。我是朱莉。
Oh, hi Julie. How are you?
哦，嗨，朱莉。你好吗？
Actually, I'm feeling quite ill today.
其实，我今天感觉很不舒服。
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that. What's wrong?
哦，听到这个我很难过。怎么了？
I think I'm coming down with the flu. I have a headache, a sore throat, a runny nose and
我想我得了流感。我头痛、喉咙痛、流鼻涕，
I'm feeling slightly feverish.
还有点发烧。
I see. So, you're calling in sick.
我明白了。所以，你是在请病假。
Yes. I was hoping to take the day off to recover.
是的。我想请一天假来恢复一下。
Okay then. Try and get some rest.
好吧。那尽量多休息。
Marco do you think he believed her?
马可，你觉得他相信她了吗？
No, I don't think he believed her. He didn't sound really convinced.
不，我觉得他没信。他听起来不太确信。
Yes, and Julie didn't sound really sick, huh?
是啊，而且朱莉听起来也不像真生病了，对吧？
Exactly. Well, we have some really good vocabulary here. Amiro, why don't you begin with the
没错。好了，我们这里有一些很好的词汇。阿米罗，你先从
first one?
第一个开始吧？
The first phrase I've chosen for you is a very, very useful one. I'm feeling quite ill
我为你选的第一个短语非常非常有用。我今天感觉很不舒服。
today.
今天。
I'm feeling quite ill today.
我今天感觉很不舒服。
Alright. What does this mean exactly?
好的。这到底是什么意思？
It means that she's feeling sick.
意思就是她感觉不舒服。
Oh, okay. That's clear. So, she is sick. She's feeling sick.
哦，好的。明白了。所以她生病了，她感觉不舒服。
Okay, let's look at another really useful phrase and this one is I'm coming down with
好的，我们来看另一个非常有用的短语，这个短语是“我得了”
the flu.
流感。
I'm coming down with the flu.
我得了流感。
Alright and this phrase means that I am starting to get the flu or I am getting the flu.
好的，这个短语的意思是，我开始得流感了，或者说我快要得流感了。
Okay. The next phrase I have for you is calling in sick.
好的。我要给你的下一个短语是“打电话请病假”。
Calling in sick.
打电话请病假。
It means calling your boss to tell him that you can't come to work today. I personally
意思是打电话给你的老板，告诉他你今天不能来上班。我个人
love this phrase because it saves so much time and explanations.
很喜欢这个短语，因为它省了很多时间和解释。
Okay, perfect. So, if I say this then everyone will know that I am not coming to work today.
好的，完美。所以，如果我说这个，大家就会知道我今天不来上班了。
Yes, definitely.
是的，没错。
Perfect. Alright. And the last phrase that we're going to take a look at today is I was
完美。好的。我们今天要看的最后一个短语是“我本来想请一天假”。
hoping to take the day off.
我本来想请一天假。
I was hoping to take the day off.
Right. And she says this to ask for permission because she does not want to go to work.
对。她这么说是在请求许可，因为她不想去上班。
Okay. Now, couldn't she just say like I can't come today?
好的。难道她不能直接说“我今天来不了”吗？
Right. She could say I can't come today but that would be a little bit impolite.
对。她可以说“我今天来不了”，但那会有点不礼貌。
Okay. So, when she says I was hoping to take the day off, it's a polite way of asking.
好的。所以，当她说“我本来想请一天假”时，这是一种礼貌的请求方式。
It's a polite way. Exactly. Because she is talking to her boss.
这是一种礼貌的方式。没错。因为她是在和老板说话。
Very good. So, let's listen to the dialogue one more time.
非常好。那么，我们再听一遍对话。
The dialogue is a little different this time. Listen carefully and see if you think the
这次对话有点不同。仔细听，看看你是否觉得
boss believes her this time.
老板这次相信了她。
Hello, Daniel speaking. How may I help you?
你好，我是丹尼尔。有什么可以帮你的？
Hi Daniel. Julie here.
嗨，丹尼尔。我是朱莉。
Oh, hi Julie. How are you?
哦，嗨，朱莉。你好吗？
Actually, I'm feeling quite ill today.
其实，我今天感觉很不舒服。
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that. What's wrong?
哦，听到这个我很遗憾。怎么了？
I think I'm coming down with the flu. I have a headache, a sore throat, a runny nose and
我想我快要得流感了。我头痛、喉咙痛、流鼻涕，而且
I'm feeling slightly feverish.
感觉有点发烧。
I see. So, you're calling in sick?
我明白了。所以，你是打电话请病假？
Yes. I was hoping to take the day off to recover.
是的。我本来想请一天假来恢复。
Okay then. Try and get some rest.
那好吧。尽量多休息。
Okay, guys. We're back and I do think he believed her this time.
好了，各位。我们回来了，我确实觉得他这次相信了她。
Yeah, I think he was understanding when he said, okay then, try and get some rest.
是的，我觉得他理解，当他说“那好吧，尽量多休息”时。
Yeah, and Julie sounded pretty sick.
是的，朱莉听起来病得很重。
Yes, yes she did.
是的，她确实听起来病得很重。
Yeah, it was convincing.
嗯，很有说服力。
Well, you know what? I almost called in sick last week.
你知道吗？我上周差点请病假。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, I wasn't feeling very well and so I almost didn't come to work.
是的，我感觉不太舒服，所以差点没来上班。
Oh, that would have been really bad for me. I would have been stuck here without you, Marco.
哦，那对我来说可就糟透了。要是没有你，马可，我就得被困在这儿了。
Yeah, you would have had to do the podcast all by yourself.
是啊，你就得一个人做播客了。
Oh no.
哦不。
You know, actually, I had the same symptoms as Julie. I also had a headache and I had
你知道吗，其实我和朱莉有一样的症状。我也头疼，而且
a sore throat and also the worst thing and the thing that I hate the most is I had a
喉咙痛，最糟糕的是，我最讨厌的是我还
runny nose.
流鼻涕。
Oh no, that's really bad because then you have to like blow your nose all the time and
哦不，那真的很糟糕，因为你就得一直擤鼻涕，然后
then it gets red and it hurts, right?
鼻子就变红，还疼，对吧？
Exactly, yeah. Luckily, I didn't have a fever though.
没错，是啊。幸运的是，我没发烧。
Oh, thank God.
哦，谢天谢地。
So did you take some medicine and it just killed everything?
那你吃了药，就把所有症状都治好了？
Yeah, I had a friend and he had some pills for the flu and he just gave me a couple and
是啊，我有个朋友，他有治流感的药，就给了我几片，
I felt better in about two days.
大约两天后我就感觉好多了。
Oh, great. Well, so guys, let me tell you about a very funny thing that really happens
哦，太好了。那么，各位，让我告诉你们一件在埃及现实生活中
in real life in Egypt.
非常有趣的事情。
What story do you have for us today?
你今天给我们带来了什么故事？
Well, it's actually not a story. It's a fact. I mean, people in Egypt, when they're sick,
嗯，其实不是故事，是个事实。我的意思是，在埃及，人们生病时，
they never call in sick themselves. They'll have someone do that for them.
从来不会自己打电话请假。他们会让别人代劳。
Oh, that's interesting. Why? Why do they do this?
哦，真有意思。为什么？他们为什么要这样做？
Well, there is this weird speculation about, you know, if you can make it to the phone, you can make it to the office.
嗯，有一种奇怪的说法是，如果你能走到电话旁，你就能走到办公室。
I agree. I agree. If I were a boss, I would do the same thing.
我同意。我同意。如果我是老板，我也会这么做。
Yeah.
是啊。
All right, listeners, we're out of time today, but be sure to visit our website at EnglishPod.com
好了，听众们，今天的时间到了，但一定要访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，
where you can see other lessons and also you can leave your questions and comments at our
在那里你可以看到其他课程，也可以在社区论坛上
community forum.
留下你的问题和评论。
We hope you enjoyed our lesson and tomorrow we will be back with another fantastic lesson
希望你喜欢我们的课程，明天我们会带来另一堂精彩的课程。
for you. But for now, it's bye.
但现在，再见。
Bye.
再见。